

+(90) 553 417 5130

ege.ozcelik@icloud.com

Bornova / İZMİR

in <u>Linkedin / Ege Özçelik</u>

<u>egeozcelik.github.io</u>

https://github.com/egeozcelik

# ABOUT

Before starting my professional career, I had the opportunity to develop myself in many different areas such as electric, electronics and communication. I have successfully undertaken various projects in different programming languages and fields, with a strong focus on software development for the last 5 years, which is the field in which I want to continue my career. My ability to quickly learn new languages independently has been instrumental in my development, reflecting both my adaptability and my enthusiasm for constant learning. Since the field I want to specialize in is the software industry, I am open to learning new languages and technologies. Being passionate about this field, I use local and foreign resources effectively to overcome difficulties and contribute effectively to team collaborations.

# EDUCATION

#### **ELECTRICAL & ELECTRONICS ENGINEERING**

Ege University / Izmir, Turkey 2017-2023

#### **ASP.NET CERTIFICATION PROGRAM**

Bilge Adam Academy(320hr.) / Izmir, Turkey 2019-2020

# EXPERIENCE

## SCHNEIDER ELECTRIC (INTERNSHIP I & II)

High Voltage Test Laboratory Assistant Manisa / Turkey 2023

# VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCES

#### IT COORDINATOR

Board of European Students Technology 2019-2021

# IT TEAM MEMBER

EGE Bilim ve Teknoloji Topluluğu 2021-2023

#### **BUILT-IN CHARGING UNIT TEAM MEMBER**

Ege ElectroMobile Team 2020-2021

## CERTIFICATES

MICROSOFT 20486 ASP.NET MVC 5 WEB APPLICIATIONS CERTIFICATE(MCA)

2020 JUNE

MICROSOFT 20480 HTML5 WITH JAVASCRIPT AND CSS3 CERTIFICATE(MCA)

2020 JUNE

.NET DEVELOPMENT EDUCATION CERTIFICATE 2020 JUNE

**UI PATH RPA EDUCATION CERTIFICATE** 2020 MARCH

BAMBU GAMIFICATION CERTIFICATE OF PARTICIPATION

2020 MARCH

# **PROJECTS**

#### **PLAYARD**

2020 - present

Playard is an open-source educational game console that we are developing with a team 4 people. Users can play games on this esp32-based portable console, and they can develop their own games on the website we are developing. We are also planning to develop an educational platform for this console where they can learn how to make games and code. You can visit our website for the details of the project and the development process.

# SMART COMMUNICATION SYSTEMS FOR EMERGENCY VEHICLES

2023

• In my thesis project, I designed modules that enable emergency vehicles to communicate with civilian vehicles in real time until they reach the target destination, and to keep in constant communication according to the situation of vehicles and traffic. These modules work in sync with the programming of transceivers, gps, microcontrollers and tft displays using LoRa technology on 433MHz.

#### FREELANCE & PERSONAL PROJECTS

 You can review both my freelance work and personal projects on my <u>github profile</u>, using programming languages such as C/C++, C#, java, javascript and react and etc.

#### **MOBILE GAMES**

2019 - present

 I am making games as a hobby to improve my algorithm skills. Some of the mobile games that I developed and published on google play. You can check it <u>here</u> for games and codes are stored in my github profile.

# SKILLS

- Embedded Systems and Microcontrollers
  - CubeIDE, Micropython, Arduino
- Full-Stack Development
  - Asp.Net, MERN
- C/C++ Programming
  - CodeBlocks, VS Code
- SQL and Database Management
  - MSSQL Server, Oracle
- 2D & 3D Game Development
  - Unity, Unreal Engine 5
- Robotic Process Automation
  - UiPath
- Deep Knowledge of OOP
  - Layered Software Architecture Design
  - Effective SOLID and OOP Principles Usage
- C# Design Patterns
  - Singleton, Builder, Unit of Work, Factory etc.
- CI/CD
  - Jenkins
- Version Control Systems
  - Git
- Project Management Tools
  - Notion, Jira, Trello, Github and SourceTree

# LANGUAGE

- Turkish (Native)
- English (★★★★☆)
- Deutsch (★★☆☆☆)

## **HOBBIES**

- Camping & Traveling
- Playing Guitar & Piano
- Snowboarding
- Playstation Games

## REFERENCES

- Tuğçe Yendim
  Data Engineer, TESLA
  +49 176 81449457
- -Will be added if needed

## DRIVING LICENSE

- B
- B1